Finding Aid for the John Gilmore Papers LSC.1144
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Indiana Twilight, 1979-80
  - 2nd draft complete., Various pagings, ca. 124 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - First final draft (shooting script) with changes in 2nd draft by Gilmore., March 1980.; 115 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Revisions, October 13, 1980.; 12 leaves. Carbon typescript and typescript (photocopy). (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 2nd final script (shooting script) with rewritten pages., 115 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Notes for various drafts, carbon copies of scenes, writer's notes for changes, etc.; a collection of unorganized notes pertaining to the development of the screenplay., ca. 175 leaves. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- The Tucson Murders
  (formerly oversize package, now oversize box) [retyped 6/98 dl]
  - Photographs used as illustrations. (Box 12)
    Mounted on posterboard with overlays marked "shooting copy," and with other annotations.
- Non Fiction
  - Laura Ingalls
    - Research Material
      - [Former] confidential files on Julia Kraus, Associated with Laura Ingalls., 1940s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Photocopies of FBI files, 1940s. (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
  - Bradley Marc Minkoff
    - Research material, 1990-1992. (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Minkoff was tried for murder of his half brother. Gilmore had been introduced to him, because of interest in James Dean.
- Fiction / Poetry
  - Various Titles
    - Manuscript Material
      - [Miscellaneous titles], 1962-1976. (Box 16, Folder 8)
        All titles: "Stop-over in Hang Tree," "Heat," Dragonfly (novel), "Carhop murder" (poem).
- Material Collected
  - Phoebe Legere
    - Press Material, 1990s. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Photocopied clippings, etc.
- Non Fiction
  - Hanging Jail
    - Research Material
      - Photograph of John Gilmore at the jail, copy of book., 1985-1987. (Box 17, Folder 5)
        Copy of book printed 1926, about the trial and jail in DeRidder, Louisiana.
- Unknown Writing
  - "La Pickpockets"
    - Research material, v.d.; Photocopies. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      re Los Angeles pickpockets by Oscar O'Lear, LAPD.
      Pickpocket specialist, friend of Robt T. Gilmore, Jr, LAPD.
- Unknown
  - Lynn Lifshin
    - Manuscripts, Letters, Clippings
      - Publications of poems, etc., 1980s-1990.; An extensive file. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Poems
      - Copies, with some photographs., 1977-1990. (Box 19, Folder 5)
        JG: Exchanges between JG and LL, S&M relationship, reflected in Lifshin's poetry.
- Play
  - Everyone Has Emptiness at 3 o'clock in the Morning
    - Manuscript material, 1987.; Copy. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- General Writing
  - Various Items
    - Correspondence and ephemera, v.d., including 1990s. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      re his writing and research.
- Donald Wolfe correspondence concerning Severed, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Final script for Severed, 2005; Hollywood, CA. (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Pictures of Barabara Payton and Wonderland Murder scene shots, 2004-2005; Hollywood, CA. (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Unbound published galley of Inside Marilyn Monroe (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Concept notes for movie script for Bombay Beach, 2004-2005; Hollywood, CA. "Notes, drafts of scenes, handwritten notes, versions." (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Rough draft of movie script for Bombay Beach (folder 1 of 2), Hollywood, CA. "Gilmore's handwritten notes throughout, rewrites, etc." (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Rough draft of movie script for Bombay Beach (folder 2 of 2), Hollywood, CA. "Gilmore's handwritten notes throughout, rewrites, etc." (Box 22, Folder 7)
- First draft of movie script for Bombay Beach, 2005; Los Angeles, CA. (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Final proof for Crazy Streak, 2005; Los Angeles, CA. (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Final proof for Inside Marilyn Monroe, 2007; Hollywood and Studio City, CA. (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous concerning Marilyn Monroe, 2006-2007; Hollywood and Studio City, CA. Interview with John Gilmore regarding Marilyn Monroe relationship, excerpt from forthcoming biography on Gilmore My Naked Life to be published in 2009. (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Final proof of Hollywood Boulevard, including Midwest book review (folder 1 of 2), 2004-2005; Hollywood, CA, New Mexico. (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Final proof of Hollywood Boulevard, including Midwest book review (folder 2 of 2), 2004-2005; Hollywood, CA, New Mexico. (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Original draft of You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood (alternate title: Hollywood Boulevard) (folder 1 of 2), 1999-2004; Novel begun 1999 (?) in Albuquerque, NM and finished in 2004 under the title of Hollywood Boulevard. (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Original draft of You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood (alternate title: Hollywood Boulevard) (folder 2 of 2), 1999-2004; Novel begun 1999 (?) in Albuquerque, NM and finished in 2004 under the title of Hollywood Boulevard. (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Rough proof for Inside Marilyn Monroe, 2007; Hollywood, CA. (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Partial manuscript and proof for L.A. Despair, 2005; Hollywood, CA. (Box 24, Folder 3)
- L.A. Times West Magazine, 2006 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- L.A. Despair (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Crazy Streak (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Inside Marilyn Monroe, 2007 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Rough draft of movie script for Severed, 2005; Studio City, CA. (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Notes for The Dragonfly, 1997; Notes were incorporated into novel Fetish Blonde published by Creation Books. (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Assorted letters, research, and memos, 1996-1999; New York, CA, Paris, France, London, England, Hollywood, CA, New Mexico. (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Motion picture script for Swamp Blood, 2004-2005; Los Angeles, CA. Written in 1991 and later revised in 2004-2005. (Box 25, Folder 4)
- First draft of the first section of Heartbreak Highway, 2006; Studio City, Ca. Novel to be published Fall, 2009 by Warner Books. (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Notes, memos, drawings, and story board ideas for draft work of Bombay Beach, 2004-2005; Hollywood, CA. "Gilmore's handwritten notes, memos, drawings, story board ideas." (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Fictionalized version of Black Dahlia based on Severed, 2006; Hollywood, CA. Some notes on scenes in Chinese. (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Notes for original Severed script, research for documentary Black Dahlia, 2004-2005; Los Angeles, CA. (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Curtis Harrington memorial letter, photo of Mamie Van Dorren and Shay Astar, Filmmaker Curtis Harrington died 5/6/2007. 50 years friendship with John Gilmore. Letter to Harrington by Gilmore, read at Harrington memorial Center for Motion Picture Study on May 21, 2007. Photo of actors Mamie Van Doren and Shay Astar by Gilmore. (Box 25, Folder 9)
- First book proposal and press release for Severed, 1991-1994 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Reviews for The Garbage People, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- First draft of Bombay Beach, 2005; Los Angeles, CA. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Selected interviews with John Gilmore, 1997-2007 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Book signings and readings, 1991-2006 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Press books (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Interviews, press reviews, magazine and newspaper coverage, 2003-2007, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Press reviews and interviews (folder 1 of 2), 1988-2007 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Press reviews and interviews (folder 2 of 2), 1988-2007 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Index Magazine, 1998, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Laid Bare proof (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Laid Bare proof (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Laid Bare first proof (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 29, Folder 3)
- Laid Bare first proof (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Fetish Blonde first draft, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Severed proof (1 of 2), 1998 (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Severed proof (2 of 2), 1998 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood first draft (1 of 2), 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood first draft (2 of 2), 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood corrected draft (1 of 3), 2001 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood corrected draft (2 of 3), 2001 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood corrected draft (3 of 3), 2001 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Hollywood Boulevard (formerly You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood) rewrite chapters (1 of 3), 2001 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Hollywood Boulevard (formerly You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood) rewrite chapters (2 of 3), 2001 (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Hollywood Boulevard (formerly You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood) rewrite chapters (3 of 3), 2001 (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Hollywood Boulevard (formerly You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood) draft (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Hollywood Boulevard (formerly You Can't Sleep in a Car in Hollywood) draft (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 31, Folder 5)